Guide to the Timothy Dwight College, Yale University, Records of the Master
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Timothy Dwight College, Yale University, records of the master
1932-1996
RU 820
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.0
(20 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda to fellows, Social Activities Committee records, and student records for the Classes of 1936-1971 maintained by the master of Timothy Dwight College, Yale University.
Timothy Dwight College (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 13-G-2 (YRG 13-G-2), Records of the master of Timothy Dwight College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is restricted. See Collection Contents for details. Accession 2018-A-0045 is open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda to fellows, Social Activities Committee records, and student records for the Classes of 1936-1971 maintained by the master of Timothy Dwight College, Yale University.
Biographical / Historical
The title "Master" for chief executive officers of residential colleges was changed to "Head of College" in April of 2016.
College students; Student housing; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Timothy Dwight College (Yale University); Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Student housing; Yale University -- Students
- Administrative and student records of the master, 1932-1971; Accession 19ND-A-372
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2047
  - Student records, 1932-1971
    - Classes of 1936-1953
      - Goring, Roger Carson, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Taylor, William Curtis, 1934-1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Loose photographs, unidentified, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Class of 1954
    - Class of 1955
      - Fenn, Richard K., 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 129A)
    - Class of 1956
    - Class of 1957
    - Class of 1958
    - Class of 1959
    - Class of 1960
    - Class of 1961
    - Class of 1962
    - Class of 1963
    - Class of 1964
    - Class of 1965
    - Class of 1966
    - Class of 1967
    - Class of 1968
    - Class of 1969
    - Class of 1971 (partial)
  - Class lists and associated documents, 1945-1964
    - Classes of 1948-1953, 1945-1957 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Classes of 1954-1961, 1951-1961 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Class of 1962, 1956-1962 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Class of 1963, 1960-1963 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Class of 1964, 1961-1964 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Student lists, including military service status, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Membership lists -- in confusion, 1942-1957 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Recommendation letters of Charles H. Sawyer, 1948-1956 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - "Alumni Directory: Timothy Dwight College in Yale University", 1940 spring (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - "The Weathervane of Timothy Dwight College in Yale University: Class of 1944", 1942 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Administrative records, 1935-1965
    - Correspondence
      - Administrative, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Former students in military service, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 2-6)
      - Deane Keller while in the Army, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Newsletters to former Timothy Dwight students in the military services, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Council of Masters meeting minutes
      - 1935-1940 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - 1947-1955 (Box 12, Folder 10-19)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Annual reports - Yale Athletic Association, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Ration books, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Health Department seminars: Problems of the Yale Student, 1950-1953 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "Town Crier of Timothy Dwight College", 1947-1957 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Gordon Cup (senior dinners), 1944-1957 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Fellows in Timothy Dwight
      - Sometimes fellows (living), 1939-1961 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
      - Sometimes fellows (deceased), 1940-1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Meetings, etc. - through CHS, 1945-1957 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
      - Chubb- Associate Chubb Fellow - past, 1949-1961 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Christmas arrangements, Timothy Dwight College, 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence concerning Timothy Dwight memorabilia, 1935-1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - History of Timothy Dwight (the elder), 1939-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 11, Box 17, Folder 1)
    - History of Timothy Dwight (the younger), 1939-1942, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Timothy Dwight (College) story, 1936-1940 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Calendar cuts (drawings by KRZ), 1957-1959 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Music - Timothy Dwight College - Glee Club (Grunyons), programs, songs, etc., 1941-1945 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of portraits of Frederick A. Godley and James Grafton Rogers by Deane Keller, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Master communications
      - On the rostrum, 1954-1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Through the "Town Crier", 1953-1961 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - On the bulletin board, 1956-1962 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Mott Woolley Memorial, 1939-1944 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Dramatics -- Timothy Dwight College - J. Stephen Knight in charge, 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Workshop - Timothy Dwight College, 1938-1944 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Picnics, 1941-1944 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Field Day, 1937-1942 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Garden Party, 1936-1940 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Gifts to the college - miscellaneous, 1936-1944 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "Timothy Dwight College", 1935 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Timothy Dwight odds and ends, 1935-1946 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Samples of lecture announcement, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - The Master with himself (poems by C. Bergin), 1946-1960, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Scrapbook (photographs), Undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Encyclopedia of Timothy Dwight College -material compiled by George Allen, 1940-1944 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - "The Three Gifts of Christmas: A Meditation," by Charles Garside, Jr., 1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "T.D. Lit", Circa 1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Visiting Fellowships in Timothy Dwight College", Circa 1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "The Chubb Fellowship in Timothy Dwight College", 1959 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "The Weathervane"
      - 1936-1938 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - 1939-1941 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - 1957 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia, 1935-1941, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Scope and Contents
      Items include photographs, articles, clippings, correspondence, songs, and drawings.
    - Photographs, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Administrative and committee records, 1950-1975; Accession 2001-A-174
  The materials are open for research.
  - Master's letters, 1950-1972 (Box 1)
  - Master's letters to fellows, 1954-1968 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1956-1975 (Box 1)
  - Social activities committee, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - General information, UG activities, facilities, circa 1950 (Box 1)
- Mellon Senior Forum records, 1990-1996; Accession 2018-A-0046
  - Correspondence and ephemera, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)